The remarkable story of three families.
Earth is a documentary film directed by Alastair Fothergill.
An epic story of adventure, starring some of the most magnificent
and courageous creatures alive, awaits you in EARTH.
Disneynature brings you a remarkable story of three animal families on a journey
across our planet – polar bears, elephants and humpback whales.
Narrator (voice), played by Patrick Stewart.
Narrator (voice), played by Constantino Romero.
Narrator (voice), played by James Earl Jones.
Narrator (voice), played by Ken Watanabe.
Narrator (voice), played by Ulrich Tukur.
Narrator (voice), played by Anggun.
Earth is a 2007 nature documentary film which depicts the diversity
of wild habitats and creatures across the planet.
The film begins in the Arctic in January of one year and moves southward,
concluding in Antarctica in the December of the same year.
Along the way, it features the journeys made by three particular species—the polar bear, African bush elephant and
humpback whale—to highlight the threats to their survival in the face of rapid environmental change.
A companion piece to the 2006 BBC Worldwide/Discovery Channel/NHK/Canadian Broadcasting Corporation television series Planet Earth, the film
uses many of the same sequences, though most are edited differently, and features previously unseen footage not seen on TV.
A British-German co-production, Earth was directed by Planet Earth executive producer Alastair Fothergill and
Mark Linfield, the producer of Planet Earth's "From Pole to Pole" and "Seasonal Forests" episodes.
It was produced by BBC, Discovery, BBC Natural History Unit and Greenlight
Media, with Discovery Network providing some of the funding.
The British release featured narration from Patrick Stewart and was distributed by Lionsgate UK, while the German release
was narrated by Ulrich Tukur and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures under Universum Film.
Earth premiered in France on 10 October 2007, before releasing in the United Kingdom
that same year on 16 November, and in Germany on 12 January 2008.
Additionally, the American version, narrated by James Earl Jones and runs 9 minutes shorter than its
international counterparts, was later released on 22 April 2009, by Disney under their Disneynature label.
With total worldwide box office revenue exceeding $100 million, Earth is the
second-highest-grossing nature documentary of all time, behind March of the Penguins (2005).
A sequel, titled Earth: One Amazing Day, was released
in the United States on 6 October 2017.
It made its world premiere in Beijing.
The film explores themes of himalaya mountain range,
ocean, walrus, wildlife, antarctica.